# ABDESSAMAD JADID

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Email: abdessamadjadid@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdessamad-

jadid-b7501710a/

GitHub: https://github.com/abdessamadjadid

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

A versatile and self-motivated individual with excellent communication skills and the ability to work under pressure. Extensive experience in IT and manufacturing industries as well. Committed to imposing high quality and works on a team with a strong sense of responsibility. possess a get-it-done attitude while not compromising on quality which generates maximum impact. A very quick learner and self-starter. I had the opportunity to work on both public and private sectors with several Technologies and Tools such as: .NET MVC, .NET CORE, C #, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP, RELATIONAL DATABASES (SQL SERVER, MYSQL AND ORACLE), SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE / DESIGN PATTERNS, PHP, BASH SCRIPT, VISUAL STUDIO, PL / SQL, SOURCETREE, BITBUCKET, JIRA.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Company: Midas Solutions (March, 2019 - Present)

Location: Brazil, São Paulo, Ribeirão Preto

Function: Full Stack Developer

Details: Worked directly in development of a management, validation and storage software of invoices to

comply with Brazilian laws.

## Main activities:

Work with C # programming languages.

- Using WEB systems development ASP.NET MVC
- Work with HTML 5, jQuery and Bootstrap
- · Working with Relational Database
- Create queries, stored procedures, functions, triggers using SQL.
- Planning and applying strategies that ensure the project's quality under development
- · Assisting identifying defects for problem solving, by meeting internal and external demands
- receiving training on company processes.

**Technologies and Tools:** NET Framework 4.6, ASP.NET MVC, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Oracle, Git, Visual Studio, PL/SQL, Jira and Bitbucket and SourceTree.

Company: 6Solutions (September, 2017 - October, 2018)

Location: Morocco, Casablanca

Function: Full Stack Developer / Customer Service.

**Details:** Worked directly with customer services for the company products. After a while, promoted to work in the development and maintenance of E-Commerce Sport system with products, sales, inventory management, payment and others via web and desktop.

**Technologies and Tools:** PHP 7, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, MySQL, Jira, Bitbucket and SourceTree.

#### Achievements:

Understand the Customer needs and combining between Customer needs and coding process.

Developing and maintaining numerous functionalities of the web and desktop application.

Company: Xerus Group (April, 2016 - , July 2016) - internship

**Location**: Morocco, Casablanca **Function**: WordPress Developer.

**Details:** Acted as a WordPress Developer of E-Commerce website, to be used to rent apartments and Houses.

Technologies and Tools: WordPress, MonsterInsights Plugin, GREENGEEK web Hosting.

**Achievements:** 

Worked on the application architecture.

Deploying the Plugin in the Website.

Company: Lydec (April, 2015 - , July 2015) - internship

**Location**: Morocco, Casablanca **Function**: Back End Developer.

**Details:** Acted as C#/.NET developer of the new card maker tool, to be used to create and design cards. **Technologies and Tools:** NET Framework 4.6, Windows Form, MS SQL Server, Visual Studio, and Git.

**Achievements:** 

Worked on the application architecture, and database design. Developed numerous functionalities of the desktop application.

## **EDUCATION**

**EMSI** (Oct 2016 – Oct 2019)

IT and Network Engineering
Option (IT methods applied to business management)

**OFPPT** (Sep 2014 – Sep 2016)

Web Development and Graphic Design

#### Baccalaureate in life and earth science

El-Majd High School (Juin -2013)

## **SKILLS**

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS	LEVEL IN 5
.NET MVC / .NET CORE	4/5
C #	4/5
HTML / CSS / JS / BOOTSTRAP	5/5
PHP	4/5
BASES DE DONNÉES RELATIONNELLES (SQL SERVER, MYSQL ET ORACLE)	4/5
NON RELATIONNEL (MONGODB)	2/5
ARCHITECTURE LOGICIELLE / DESIGN PATTERNS	3/5
BASH SCRIPT / LINUX COMMAND LINES	4/5
AI, BIG DATA, CLOUD COMPUTING (AWS, AZURE)	2/5
ROBOTIQUE (ARDUINO, RASPBERRY PI 3)	3/5
CYBER SECURITY, NETWORKING, INDUSTRY 4.0.	2/5
DÉVELOPPEMENT MOBILE (FLUTTER & DART)	3/5

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Leadership Development AIESEC (09/2019)
- Big Data Foundations Level 1 IBM (05/2018)
- HADOOP FOUNDATIONS LEVEL 1 IBM (05/2018)
- 98-364:MTA: Database Fundamentals MICROSOFT (05/2018)
- Windows® Server Administration Fundamentals MICROSOFT (05/2017)

# **LANGUAGES**

English: Full Professional Proficiency
 French: Full Professional Proficiency
 Arabic: Native or Bilingual Proficiency
 Portuguese: Elementary Proficiency
 German: Elementary Proficiency

## OTHER QUALIFICATIONS AND FEATURES

- > Create from Scratch an E-Commerce system to sell Sport products via web using payment integration.
- > Create from Scratch a Resume as a Website: https://abdessamadjadid.github.io/
- > Software architecture and software modeling like Dependency Injection and Inversion of Control.
- > Backend development with NET Core Web API and MVC.
- > Frontend development with Angular.
- > Mobile development to Android and iOS with Flutter and Dart.
- > Relational databases using SQL Server, MySQL and Oracle.
- Non-relational databases using MongoDB
- Using Linux and windows.